uh we're not quite there yet
once i get this one right here i've got
something quite special planned anyway
hello and welcome back to another
episode of hermitcraft i have had a big
brain moment like really big brain
moment so as you guys know from last
episode i've put in the floor here and i
was planning on putting my huge item
sorter in here and having this as my
main room
but then what happens to the enormous
rooms which are far more interesting in
shape
in the actual mansion
well this is where the big brain moment
came in
i think what we do is we have lots of
different farms up here
and then we actually have this looking
like more like a factory on the inside
and they all
funnel all the items they flow in
straight into the giant item sorter so
whenever i'm here i have like a control
panel in the middle
and then from there
i can decide what goes on what turns off
you know for lag reasons and then this
doesn't get wasted at all i know i was
planning on having a few mob farms in
here anyway but i'm thinking this
becomes the mega factory industrial
mansion style but before we actually
start making any
kind of machine or farm we've got to
finally
get this thing made now there's a hole
right there and it's really hard to see
and one of my favorite things that to do
at the moment is to try and fly in it's
so difficult to see it
so maybe some of you don't really know
what an item sorter is but it's
basically the redstone answer to this
mess here i put the item in and it just
filters into the correct chest and then
you end up with something to look a bit
like that where it's all items sorted
for you now for that you need a lot of
chests which explains this
giant system of trees but more
importantly you need a lot of iron now
last episode i did tell you that i left
my camera account over here in mumbo's
industrial area now hopefully he's not
here yep he's not here but i did do
mumbo an enormous favor i left my camera
account here for literally two days as
long as i possibly could to generate
iron and then i crafted it all up for
him look at all this this is all for
mumbo obviously because it's his machine
but i took a small amount for my own
endeavors and i was thinking i could use
a little room here just to just so i can
uh i can entertain myself so i wonder if
mumbo will notice if we claim one of
these real quick it's a pretty simple
change we take the eyes and we put them
up this way and then of course
add the hair in there we go it's it's
pretty much in the same style as all of
these iron golem heads or villager heads
i'm not sure what they are but look
i wonder how long it will be before he
actually notices the giant green head
that has snuck into the walls of his
industrial area to be fair if unless you
were looking you probably wouldn't
notice
so i'm thinking i make just a little
room in here maybe actually inside
inside this head
just so i can uh i can store my stuff in
here if i need to there we go this will
do for now it's just a nice little
storage room that i can i can come to if
i need to and just uh block it off
whenever i'm not using it i bet mumbo
will go the entire season without seeing
this anyway so we've got our iron we
have got our chests or you know most of
the wood for the chests and now i
believe we can start making this thing
i do have to think slightly about how
i'm going to design this so obviously
it's usually a big square because that's
how you know minecraft works a circle
won't really work in this case but i do
want like a control panel area
so this is the center as i've marked out
and i need like
a clear space
like this
either as a corridor to a place at the
back or
the control panel can be actually just
there but i want this space because it's
uh
i need that gap between all of the
chests so i'm gonna get my redstone item
sorter tutorial up from uh someone on
the internet and uh i will start the
time lapse to make this thing
and we will be reared finally of our
chest monster let's go
[Music]
so
on a scale of one to ten
how proud of me are you i have created
my very first item sorter and i've
already realized i've made a grave
mistake
this item sorter
isn't even big enough to hold half the
items in minecraft so i'm going to have
to be
very selective about which blocks make
it into the system and which don't i've
only done a few of the filters so i've
done you know the redstone block and you
know these ones here so i can actually
show you how this works now you're going
to be extra proud of me and i'm going to
say the same thing that every redstone
person ever says you ready
it's actually quite simple no really it
is it looks really complicated on the
outside of it you know like look at all
this redstone oh scary well actually
it's just the same pattern even if you
don't fully understand how it works it's
just the same pattern repeated over and
over and over again all the way around
the system as you can see you can see
it's just the same thing over and over
again
and then once you've got that repeated
pattern that blocks all of the hoppers
you then create a water stream over the
top and that pushes the items so
actually the item sort of bit is fairly
simple
what i won't say is simple is this thing
i followed a tutorial for this one and i
have no idea how it works i'll be honest
with you
if we go down into here
this is a shulker box loader
and what it does is it takes the shulker
box they all fall into this item hopper
when it's done it then gets released in
here and the empty structure box ends up
back up there i have actually adapted
this design to my own needs but yeah
this bit this bit was not so simple so
let's do a uh a little demonstration
shall we i've got here
empty shulker box will take out
the items from the filters that i've
already done all right this is where the
magic happens
we put it in
it falls down it will filter through the
items and release them into the water
stream up they go and as you can see
they're hitting the correct filter and
going straight into the right place
how amazing i mean it's going to take a
while but i basically once all the
filters are set up i take each shulker
box and i just plonk them in here and
then they will make their way round and
as you can see that one was done and the
empty shulker box
comes back this is the miracle of
automatic item sorting and now it's done
you can see they're all
in the right place i'm 10 out of 10
proud of me for this one but that's only
half of the puzzle so we've got our
items we have to get 41 of each item in
order to create the filters but i think
that is definitely a job for off-camera
green because uh that's that's gonna be
dull gathering all these different
things what won't be dull is actually
decorating this room we can't leave it
like this at all this is not good what
i'm gonna do is add a few pillars in
here i quite like how this is shaping
the room but it definitely needs more so
we're going to hop straight back into
another time lapse and we're going to
decorate this just a little bit not the
full thing but make this look a bit more
epic are we ready let's go
[Music]
this is looking slightly better
obviously i'm still not finished look at
the state of the ceiling well there is
no state of the ceiling it's just one
big stone slab and there's obviously
still some more work to be done on these
bits as well
but i think for for the time being i'm
absolutely sick of this room however i
am very very happy with how this has all
come out and it's given me some more
inspiration for how to make this better
now i did actually i know i said i
wasn't going to but i did actually spend
a long time
setting up some filters of just the
items that i have in my possession and
use fairly frequently and that has left
very few spaces left there's a gap for
some stuff so i've blocked these off for
the time being and what i'm going to do
essentially
is um actually start loading up just
these few shulker boxes and i'm just
gonna see what happens make sure that it
works and we'll uh we'll see what we'll
see how this goes in the end
everything that's not being filtered is
ending up back here in the trash
department and then when this is all
full i'll be able to get a good idea of
what i need to create a filter for and
what i use quite a lot of but yeah let's
just watch this go for a second
[Music]
do
okay seriously we're about half an hour
later and it's still going it's emptied
four shulker boxes though which is uh
pretty good
but it's uh it's still going so we're
gonna let we'll let it just we'll let it
ride we'll check the junk box you can
see it's filtered quite a lot of it so
what i need to find out is white dye
might be one
like grade i might be one torches might
be one but all the others are just one
anyway i think that is more than enough
of that room for today i did notice
while i was flying around there was a
little box up there with a sign on it
thanks pesky bird
rd
is that a face oh no no it's red dog
i'm like i'm like turning my head
sideways like is that a is that a weird
xd face no no it's
look at that
70 diamonds you can kill my pesky bird
did he joke okay so
oh
oh ren you were about you were this
close this close to incurring my wrath
that does beg the question where is the
pesky bird and what is that
i got another box dear hermit thank you
for being a valued customer of my lucky
lookie at my bookie i love your face and
to show your appreciate our appreciation
here is a little goodie box as a token
of our gratif or our gratitude thank you
he has want to buy a book
i'll be honest i don't i don't think
i've had i don't think i've had many
books i i kind of got my own books this
season but um you know if you want to
whoa
that is some custom goodies there look
dark prismarine he knows
he knows thank you corrales maybe i will
go and looky looky at the bookie
get some uh get some cool stuff here
he's he's yeah he's got
anvils he's got sixty two stacks of
anvils
that's pretty good
that's pretty good you know we're doing
pretty good on the diamond front 25
diamond blocks not bad at all now that
we've made some decent progress in that
room i actually want to head over to the
shopping district because there's
something
i should have actually done a while ago
and
and that is open up the town hall the
mayor race has
actually begun but b dubs told me that
he wanted to do some interior work so i
thought i'd come over here and check it
out the town hall is officially open the
diamond throne
is there for the taking
wow b-dubs has done a really nice job oh
wow okay that mushroom block as a
ceiling block is fantastic
i like the little details
good job b-dubs this is looking really
good really really good now um we
definitely need something a bit nicer
for this
uh but once we have the names of who's
going to be running
then
then we can fix this all up i need to
let's have a closer look upstairs
because this is looking pretty cool oh
and when when the mayor's elected they
can look over the shopping district
everything that the light touches is
yours
so this is all looking pretty good
but i want to take this
one step further just putting posters
everywhere isn't going to win the race
for mumbo
we need a proper headquarters i'm pretty
sure mumbo now knows that he's running
for mayor but i still haven't spoken to
him about it it's really weird so mumbo
knows that i'm like
campaigning for him
but he hasn't actually said anything
which is actually really hilarious
so what i'm thinking is we make
a headquarters a campaigning
headquarters of some kind not in the
shopping district itself because this is
for shops but maybe we can make our own
little island somewhere out to sea
oh my goodness
all right well maybe not too close to
anyone's base but
there we go that's kind of raised off
the ground a bit so i could make a
little custom island here
and on the top
mumbo hq m4 mfm mumbo for mayor
headquarters
fortunately for me not a single soul has
been buying dirt so i can just uh
commandeer my own dirt from the shop
maybe it's too expensive one diamond for
three stacks maybe it could be one
diamond for four stacks
and uh yeah i'll use i'll just use this
i'll just use this to make it i have no
idea what to build here so what we'll
start with
is uh just making this island
and then we'll think about the build
after that
we'll probably just start with a dirt
house
that i think that's that is very
symbolic we'll start with the dirt house
and then we'll do it like let's let's
make this thing really quick
[Music]
uh now that i've actually got the island
all the way to the surface it was a lot
it was a lot taller than i thought it
would be and we've actually got the the
smallest island i've uh
ever seen
to build something proper on so this is
uh not gonna be easy we're gonna start
small
we're just straight up gonna start
really small i can't decide whether this
amazing town hall draws the eye
or does the giant weird plant monster
with eyes do that it's a pretty close
competition anyway let's make this
humble shack
okay
this is
the saddest island this is the saddest
minecraft island i've ever seen
it is it is pitiful but this is where
we're gonna start until we can figure
out exactly what kind of headquarters we
want to make
so for now it will be as simple as mumbo
for
[Music]
mayor this is terrible this is really
terrible and i'm not even ashamed to
admit it it is it is really terrible but
you know you've got to start somewhere
and until i get a good idea for a nice
tall building and of course get the
resources for it
this is where we start
mumbo for mayor
here we go
you know from a distance
this looks so funny i mean it's just the
most pathetic wooden shack you've ever
seen
oh my goodness now speaking of mumbo
jumbo he actually let me know and so did
a bunch of you guys in the comments
about the door situation so as you guys
know i have to steal all the doors
forever
for this entire season
now some people have been actually
really really smart i don't see any door
on this base i don't i don't know how to
tackle this there's not a single thing
in here that would count as a door
that i can take but some people have
made something a little bit more
impressive this
is tango's
toon towers base and i've got to say
let's just take a minute
to appreciate this because oh my
goodness doesn't this look special
this is a a nice style it's different it
stands out and we got to respect the
concrete because i mean that's a lot of
materials
but here's what i was informed of
tango's door is of course a big fancy
redstone door still a door though isn't
it
still a door don't grumble at me over
there
it's it's a door
and since this is broken now normally i
wouldn't touch anything quite as
complicated as this i mean this is
insane but you know people have let me
know that this has got to be rebuilt
anyway and so this is probably the only
opportunity where it will be absolutely
okay
for me to take this door
so i'm gonna seize the opportunity i'm
gonna do tango a favor by clearing this
out because this has got to be remade i
assume by mumbo
oh and scar just died to a golem you
know that's really funny because he he
literally said to me on discord two
seconds ago i'm experimenting with
villagers
oh honey blocks ivory honestly i haven't
played with these at all
they make the most disgusting noises
can i can you fly out of these nope oh
yes you can
now if i went straight up that would
mean that this would break my fall
that's awesome oh my goodness how deep
does this thing go this wasn't this
isn't what i signed up for this is
really complicated oh my goodness a lot
of serious redstoning went into this
i have been i have been assured don't
worry i have been assured that this is
beyond repair and it needs completely
gutting so i there's nothing here that
can be salvaged at all if you know
anything about
her honey slime block machines
then you know
that this is beyond repair
i'm doing them a favor so i reckon i can
leave all the furnaces because they
wouldn't move anyway
so it's only really like the stuff here
that's the actual door so i'll leave
that for them now i feel terrible about
this i feel really terrible because you
know this is a lot of resources that i'm
uh taking away so what i'm actually
going to do
just to make this ease my conscience a
little bit what i'm going to do
is leave a chest and i'm gonna leave
roughly the right amount of diamonds
to buy all the materials you would need
to fix up this door so observers honey
block slime block sticky piston and
white concrete i think that should
be enough to replace all the materials
because you know the rules of this door
thing aren't really established but if
i'm gonna steal the door i've gotta
actually steal the door i can't just
dismantle it and leave it in a pile but
there's uh there's another problem
that's just occurred to me i gotta
remake this door at some point to store
it that's not gonna go well oh my
goodness he's got he's got uh
he's got a hermit and herald
button man mare oh my goodness turns out
mumbo's actually getting some uh
coverage in the old newspaper here
newspaper uncovers secret campaign oh
it's not so secret anymore oh this is
just saying that there's a secret
campaign for him to be uh him to be
mayor well
surprise
already out there wow that looks so cool
looks so cool i'm sorry i am so sorry
for having to take that
and i hope that it is successful on the
second time round but i'm going to take
this door back to the base you've
probably been wondering where i've been
storing all my doors well i've got a box
called more doors
and that is exactly where this lot is
going for now
so when the time comes that we make the
door dungeon this will be tango's door
and i'll have to try and remake it but i
am afraid that is all we have time for
today i'm gonna actually start loading
up some more shulker boxes into the
machine because as we've noticed it's
gonna take several hours for it all to
get processed so all there is left to
say is thank you very much for watching
i hope you enjoyed this episode and all
the crazy long hours of work that went
into it and i'll see you in the next
episode good bye